Guide to the Max Wilk Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- October 2016 Acquisition, 1930s-2000s; 39; 15.67; (15 boxes)
  - Audiovisual materials
    - Film reels
      - Mine!, Barbara Wilk, undated; 1 (Box 152)
      - Letters from an Apache, undated; 1 (Box 152)
      - Letter from an Apache, Barbara Wilk, undated; 1 (Box 152)
      - Letter from an Apache, narrator track, undated; 1 (Box 152)
      - Letter from an Apache, music track, undated; 1 (Box 152)
      - Letter from an Apache, undated; 1 (Box 152)
      - Mine, undated; 1 (Box 152)
      - Six reels of Queen Victoria and the Indians, circa 1980s; 6 (Box 153)
      - Two reels of Mine, undated; 2 (Box 154)
      - Seven reels of untitled, undated; 7 (Box 154)
  - Electronic media
    - Shannon, unlabled, undated; 3 (Box 150)
    - Max Wilk - Schlocks, undated; 1 (Box 150)
- September 2017 Acquisition, 1928-2011; 40; 14.33; (15 boxes)
  Boxes 163-164 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Writings, 1975-2008, undated (Box 155)
    Contains notes, research files, and writings including War on Park Avenue, Buster and Ed, Leicester Square, Mean Creek or How to Write a Hit, Danny Boy, Tony Bennett and the Indians, Mad Dogs and Englishmen, Jonathan Winters Presents 200 Years of American Humor, Father!, notes on comedy and comedians, Has Anybody Seen my Warhol, along with other stories and essays.
  - Writings, circa 1950-2008, undated (Box 156)
    Contains notes, research files, sheet music and writings including You Must Remember This, Wowoweeweewoh!, Golden Summer, Somewhere There's Music, How I Spent My Summer Vacation, Mad Dogs and Englishmen, Long Term Memories, Convention City, I Love to Hear Somebody Play, along with other stories, scripts, and essays.
  - Writings, 1946-2008, undated (Box 157)
    Contains notes, research files, sheet music and writings including Where Were the Beatles, My War on Park Avenue, Jack Benny in London, Mean Creek or how to Write a Hit, along with other stories, scripts, and essays.
  - Writings, 1952-2006 (Box 158)
    Contains notes, drafts, photocopies, research materials, and writings including Tony Bennett and the Indians, Picadilly Circus, Storm Warning Redux, The Beatles Yellow Submarine, and others.
  - Printed materials and ephemera, 1930-2007 (Box 159)
    Contains newspaper and magazine clippings, scrapbooks, photographs, artwork and doodles, memorabilia, playbills, sheet music and research notes.
  - Correspondence and business files, 1928-2011 (Box 160)
    Contains correspondence with Groucho Mark, Ronald Reagan, P.G. Wodehouse and others. Business files include Yellow Submarine correspondence and contracts, and other related materials.
  - Photographs, printed material, and ephemera, 1944-1995 (Box 161)
    Contains printed items, photographs, and materials used for research.
  - Research materials. books, and magazines with marginalia, 1930s-1990s (Box 162)
    Also contains large format photographs.
  - Audiovisual materials
    - Reel to reel audio, circa 1959-1970
      - "Fabulous Fifties", final mix, 1959 December 28; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977356)
      - Lou Holtz - TV, 1959 May 4; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977364)
      - Hal Kanter on radio - TV, Tape #3, 1960 August 11; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977372)
      - Chase and Sanborn, Radio, NBC anniversary show, 1966 December; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977380)
      - Al Jolson at ease, Oct 27, 1946, WOR NY; Show business stars, 1968; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977398)
      - "The World Today Mutual", 1969 June 16; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977406)
      - Winter's TV appearance, NBC, 1970 August 10; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977414)
      - Empty, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977422)
      - Max Wilk - A Kennedy Interview, April 13; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977430)
      - Jolson at ease, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977448)
      - Shows, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977455)
        Includes "Brigadoon", "The Pirate", and Gershwin Jazz
      - 78 rpm record albums and acetates, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977463)
        Includes list of contents that notes the reel contains Irving Berlin: "Miss Liberty" selections, "This is the army" promos, Marc Blitzstein: "Regina" selections, and "The Jolson Story" soundtrack selections.
        "Just One Way to Say I Love You" - Irving Berlin
        "The Honorable Profession of the Fourth Estate" - Irving Berlin
        "Happiness is a Thing called Joe" - Irving Berlin
        "Little Black Boy" - Ethel Waters
        Kate Smith - promo
        Jimmy Durante - promo
        Al Jolson - promo
        Eddie Cantor - promo
        Walter Winchell - promo
        "California Here I Come"
        "Latin from Manhattan"
        "You Made Me Love You"
        "Waitin' for the Robert E. Lee"
        "Swanee"
        "April Showers"
        "Wings Over the Nation"
        "Can't Teach My Old Heart New Tricks" - Frances Langford
        "What Will It Be" - Scene II (Priscilla Gillette)
        "The Best Thing of All" - Scene II (Jane Pickens)
        "Finale" - Scene V (Priscilla Gillette & Jane Pickens)
        "Rain Quartette" - Scene V (Priscilla Gillette, Brenda Lewis, William Wilderman, Lillyn Brown)
        "Lionnet" - Scene V (Brenda Lewis)
      - Goodman Ace, side #2, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977471)
      - Zambetis, Bouzouki, Theodorakis/Cambanelis, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977489)
      - J Winters, 1970 September 16; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977497)
      - Mercouri Dassin, Paris (1 of 2 audiotape reels), undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977505)
      - Mercouri Dassin, Paris (2 of 2 audiotape reels), December 13; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977513)
      - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977521)
    - Livingston-Evans-Wilk songs; show, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002109977539)
      "The Broadway Way Today"
      "Why Don't They Do a Show About Us?"
      "Anywhere But Here"
      "France"
      "Tel Aviv"
      "The New Vienna Woods"
      "Hear That Band"
      "Femininity"
      "As I Love You"
      "Never Let Me Go"
      "All the Time"
      "You're So Right For Me"
      "Gee, It's Gonna Be Wonderful"
      "Mama, Where You Get de Cigar?"
      "Cincinnati"
      "That Ain't Right"
      "Through Children's Eyes"
      "Just an Honest Mistake"
    - VHS tapes, 1985-1990
      - Prairie Dog Sees, English Version, undated; 1; 00:03:21 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002109976184)
      - Prairie Dog Sees, English and Navajo Version, undated; 1; 00:06:38 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002109976192)
      - Letter from an Apache, 1985; 1; 00:13:39 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002109976200)
      - Letter from an Apache, 1985; 1; 00:12:09; Excessive video levels are clipped. (Box 164, Item barcode 39002109976218)
      - Emergence, 1985; 1; 00:16:59 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002109976226)
      - Queen Victoria and the Indians, 1985; 1; 00:12:28 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002109976234)
      - Queen Victoria and the Indians, 1985; 1; 00:12:48; Audio is distorted throughout the tape. (Box 164, Item barcode 39002109976242)
      - Time Warp, long version, Barbara Wilk, undated; 1; 00:12:59 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002109976259)
      - Barbara Wilk Show, Silvermine, April 1987; 1; 00:02:53 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002109976267)
      - Edith Discussions, 95th birthday, 1990 February; 1; 02:07:36; High white levels were recorded. Video clipping or overexposure resulted in some loss of detail. Program was recorded at a very high level. (Box 164, Item barcode 39002109976275)
      - Barbara Wilk, Connecticut artist's showcase, Hartford, undated; 1; 00:04:44; The program was recorded at a very low level. Video noise is visible in the picture. The video program features different segments exposed differently. The interview footage in the video program was shot in a low light setting, therefore it looks dark. (Box 164, Item barcode 39002109976283)
      - Dolly Curtis interviews Barbara Wilk--"Making Connections with Ancient Art", April 1989; 1; 00:30:35; Program recorded at a very high level. White levels were recorded to tape high and overexposed in areas. (Box 164, Item barcode 39002109976291)
      - Prehistoric Cave Painting: Lescaux to Altamira, undated; 1; 01:22:54; Break in program at 35:17. Visible distortion seen at times at the bottom of the program. (Box 164, Item barcode 39002109976309)
      - Mine, animated film by Barbara Wilk, 1985; 1; 00:04:37 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002109976317)
      - This is the Army: 50th Anniversary, 1992 July 4; 1; 01:56:39; This is a film transfer, there are some minor fluctuations in the color in the film print. (Box 164, Item barcode 39002109976325)
        Videocassette cover is inscribed with messages to Max Wilk from a number of people.
    - Film reels, circa 1960s-1980s
      - Out of House, A-TRK., undated; 1 (Box 165)
      - Out of House CRI, undated; 1 (Box 165)
      - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 165)
      - Four film reels unlabeled, undated; 4 (Box 166)
      - Two reels labeled "Barbara Wilk: Field Report", undated; 2 (Box 166)
      - Queen Victoria and the Indians, undated; 1 (Box 166)
      - B-roll, undated; 1 (Box 166)
      - Letter from an Apache, undated; 1 (Box 166)
      - Queen Victoria and the Indians - A track, undated; 1 (Box 166)
      - He-She, undated; 1 (Box 166)
    - Records
      - 78 rmp record, "Danger Love at Work", Alice Faye, undated; 1 (Box 167)
        Record is damaged.
      - 45 rpm records titled in Greek, undated; 3 (Box 167)
        45 rpm records are presses of Odeon under Warner Brothers.
      - 78 rpm records, Folkways, circa 1950s; 2 (Box 167)
      - 32 rpm record, Folkways, circa 1950s; 1 (Box 167)
  - Materials from film reels, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 168)
    Included are receipts, notes, and other materials accompanying the film reels located in Boxes 165-166.
  - Electronic media, circa 1990s-2006 (Box 169)
    2 CDs and a floppy disk.